Jackie Robinson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Political File, 1949-1986 (Box 5-6)
  - Powell, Adam Clayton (1908-1972), 1960-1963, undated
  - Presidential administrations
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1958
    - Kennedy, John F.
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1961-1963
      - Kennedy, Robert F., 1961-1963
    - Johnson, Lyndon B.
      - Newspaper clippings, 1965
      - Photocopies from the Lyndon B. Johnson Library, Austin, Tex., 1964-1967, undated
  - Presidential campaigns
    - 1960
      - Democratic party, 1960, 1984, undated
      - Republican party, 1960
    - 1964
      - Goldwater, Barry, 1964
      - Public response to "The GOP for White Men Only?" by Jackie Robinson, Saturday Evening Post, 1963
      - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1964
    - 1968
  - Republican party, 1960-1968
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A.
    - Correspondence, 1958-1973
    - Miscellany, 1963-1968, undated
    - Photocopies from the Rockefeller Archives Center, N. Tarrytown, N.Y., 1950-1968, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Special assistant for community affairs, 1966-1968
  - Testimony before the House Un-American Activities Committee
    - Correspondence, 1956
    - Miscellany, 1949, 1960, 1979, undated
    - Photocopies
      - Arthur Mann Papers, Library of Congress, undated
      - Branch Rickey Papers, Library of Congress, 1949-1950, 1963, undated
- Business and Corporate File, 1952-1981 (Box 6-7)
  Correspondence, memoranda, telegrams, financial and legal records, reports, minutes of meetings, printed matter, newspaper clippings, and miscellaneous items relating to Robinson's business interests following his baseball career.
  - Business proposals (Box 6)
    - Foreign, 1957, 1964-1966, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1952-1971
  - Chock Full O'Nuts
    - Antisemitism, 125th St. restaurant controversy, 1962
    - Correspondence, 1957-1963
    - Financial records, 1959-1966, undated
    - Minutes of board of directors meetings, 1961-1963
    - Miscellany, 1958, undated
    - Personnel
      - Applications, 1962
      - Correspondence, 1957-1963, undated
      - Dismissals, 1963
      - Store reports, 1962, undated
    - Public complaints and commendations, 1960-1962, undated
    - Utopia resort, Warwick, N.Y., 1962, undated
  - Conference on Equal Employment Opportunity, 1961-1964
  - Freedom National Bank of New York
    - Annual reports, 1968-1971
    - Chairman of the board of directors, 1963-1972, undated
    - Feasibility study, 1963
    - Loans and financing, 1963-1971 (Box 7)
    - Organization
      - Organizational committee
        - Announcements, 1964
        - Minutes of meetings, 1963
      - Procedures and proposals, 1963-1964, undated
    - Partnership investment, 1966-1970
    - Printed matter, 1963-1970, 1979-1981
    - Registration statements, 1970
    - Stock reports and sales, 1964-1970, undated
  - Gibraltar Life Insurance Co., 1965-1966
  - Hamilton Life Insurance Co.
    - Board of directors
      - Cochairman's file, 1966-1967
      - Minutes of meetings, 1967
      - Notice of meetings, 1966-1967
    - Stock options, 1966
  - Jackie Robinson Baseball Clinic, 1969
  - "Minority enterprise," 1956-1957, 1963-1972, undated
  - Proteus Foods, 1968-1970
  - Trans World Life Insurance Co., 1964
- Religious and Civic Activities, 1951-2001 (Box 7-8)
  Correspondence, memoranda, financial and legal records, minutes of meetings, speeches, congressional testimony, printed matter, newspaper clippings, and miscellaneous items concerning Robinson's association with church-sponsored and interfaith organizations, his support of "minority housing" and urban renewal projects, and other community-based activities.
  - Churches and interfaith organizations (Box 7)
    - Jewish organizations
      - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, 1963-1975, 1985, undated
      - Miscellaneous, 1957-1965
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-1968, undated
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1954-1956, 1964-1968, undated
    - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America, 1963-1964 (Box 8)
    - Testimony before the House Appropriations Committee, 1969
    - Texas Association of Christian Churches, eighty-first annual assembly, 1968
    - United Church Men of the United Church of Christ, 1963-1965, undated
  - Concordia College, Moorhead, Minn., founder's day dinner, 1964
  - Connecticut State Parole Board, 1955-1957, undated
  - Drug abuse, 1968-1971, undated
  - Education and youth, 1961-1968, 1987
  - "Minority housing" and urban renewal
    - Bahamas and Jamaica, 1964-1968
    - Correspondence, 1951-1968, undated
    - Jackie Robinson Construction Co., 1972, 1985, 2001
    - Jackie Robinson Garden Apartments, San Francisco, Calif., 1971
    - Memorial Recreation Forest, Warren County, N.C., 1964
    - Miscellany, 1952, 1962, 1973, undated
    - Puerto Rico, 1963
    - Testimony before the Housing Subcommittee of the Senate Committee on Banking and Currency, 1967
    - West Side urban renewal project, 1960-1967, undated
  - New York State Athletic Commission, 1971, undated
  - Young Men's Christian Association, 1953-1957, 1963-1964
  - Youth activities, 1957-1969, undated
- Subject File, 1953-1999 (Box 9-10)
  Correspondence, memoranda, financial and legal records, speeches and writings, printed matter, newspaper clippings, photocopies, and miscellaneous items relating largely to Robinson's broadcast and media activities and posthumous events.
  - Broadcast and media activities (Box 9)
    - Advertising, circa 1950s
    - "America's Town Meeting," radio broadcast, 1954
    - "Biography: Jackie Robinson," photocopies of television transcript from the Department of Special Collections, University of California, Los Angeles, Calif., 1963, undated
    - Broadcasting companies
      - WNBC, New York, N.Y., radio station, director of community activities, 1953-1954
      - WSTC, Stamford, Conn., radio station, licensing controversy, 1971
    - Correspondence, 1957-1966
    - Licensing Corp. of America, 1961
    - Miscellany, 1959, 1969
    - Negro Actors Guild of America, 1964
    - Program proposals
      - Documentary film, 1962
      - "Sports Spots," undated
    - Sports Programs, Inc., contract for ABC-TV, 1965
    - Television script, undated
    - "Youth Wants to Know," television program, 1953, 1967
  - Personal requests, 1956-1972, undated
  - Posthumous events and legacy
    - Brooklyn Dodgers Fan Club, 1987
    - California Association of Community Colleges Sports Hall of Fame, 1984
    - Commemoration of breaking major league baseball's "color line," 1977, 1987, 1997, (3 folders)
    - Commemorative stamp, 1982, 1989
    - Dedication of Jackie Robinson Stadium, University of California, Los Angeles, Calif., 1981
    - Jackie Robinson Foundation
      - Correspondence, 1989
      - "Jackie Robinson: A Search for Excellence," essay/poetry contest, 1988
      - "Jackie Robinson: An American Journey," traveling exhibit
        - National tour, 1987-1988
        - Printed matter, 1987 (Box 10)
      - Printed matter, 1987-1991, 1997-1999, undated
    - Montreal Expos, 1984-1985
    - Newspaper clippings
      - African American athletes, 1979-1981, 1987-1990
      - Campanis, Al, 1987
      - Miscellaneous, 1973, 1981
      - Sports administration, 1987-1990
    - Reference material and research papers, 1982-1989
    - Robinson Park, Pasadena, Calif., 1975
    - Sculptures and statues
      - Jackie Robinson sculpture project, 1984-1985
      - Jersey City, N.J., 1998
      - Montreal, Canada, memorial statue, 1988-1990
    - U.S. Sports Academy, Daphne, Ala., Jackie Robinson medallion, 1986-1987
  - Recreational activities, 1964
  - State department tour proposals, 1956-1961, undated
- Speeches and Writings, 1934-1999 (Box 10-15)
  Correspondence, drafts and outlines, literary contracts, notes and research material, royalty statements, book reviews, printed matter, newspaper clippings, photocopies, and miscellaneous items concerning articles, books, and speeches by and about Robinson.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Agents and associates (Box 10)
    - Duckett, Alfred, 1968-1971
    - Lester Lewis Associates, 1960, 1968-1969
    - Correspondence and contracts, 1954-1968
    - Drafts, 1948, 1962-1970, undated
    - Photocopies from the Richard M. Nixon Papers, 1958-1960, undated
  - Books
    - Correspondence and contracts, 1961-1963
    - Titles
      - Baseball Has Done It
        - Correspondence and contract, 1963-1964
        - Draft, 1964
          - Chapters 1-5
          - Chapters 6-23, (3 folders) (Box 11)
        - Royalty statement, 1970
      - Breakthrough to the Big League
        - Correspondence and reviews, 1965-1966
        - Draft, undated
      - I Never Had It Made
        - Correspondence, 1970-1971, undated
        - Drafts, 1971, undated, (2 folders)
        - Notes and research material, 1968, undated
        - Reviews, 1972
      - "My Greatest Day," unpublished
        - Drafts, undated
        - Outline, undated
      - "The Next Frontier for the American Business Community and the Negro," unpublished, 1965-1967
    - Unidentified outline, 1969
  - Motion picture, The Jackie Robinson Story, 1952-1958, 1982, undated (Box 12)
  - Speeches
    - Addresses and speeches
      - Baseball and sports
        - 100 Per Cent Wrong Club, Atlanta, Ga., 1954-1956
        - Drafts and printed matter, 1962, undated
        - Sport magazine, twenty-fifth anniversary top performers award, 1971
      - Business community and economic opportunity, 1956-1971, undated
      - Civil rights, 1957-1971, undated, (3 folders)
      - Commencement addresses, 1954, 1962, 1969-1972, undated
      - Drug addiction, 1972, undated
      - Early career and personal reminiscences, undated
      - Political
        - Drafts, notes, and reference material, 1966-1969, undated
        - Republican party, 1964-1965, undated (Box 13)
        - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1964-1966, undated
      - Religious and civic organizations, 1963-1968, undated
    - Correspondence, 1956-1970
    - Miscellany, 1960-1964, undated
  - Speeches and writings by others
    - Articles and other writings about Robinson
      - Drafts
        - Duckett, Alfred, 1967, undated
        - Eisenberg, Arthur, "Jack Roosevelt Robinson: A Biographical Portrait," 1977
        - Parrott, Harold, "Inside Jackie Robinson," 1973
        - Rudeen, Kenneth, "Jackie Robinson," undated
        - Weaver, William, "The Reaction of Negro Newspapers to Jackie Robinson's Breaking the Color Line in Baseball, 1945-1947," 1976
      - Newspaper clippings and printed matter, 1934, 1954, 1965-1992, 1999, undated, (2 folders)
    - Books
      - Bobley, Peter A., "I Remember Jackie," unpublished, 1981
      - Rowan, Carl Thomas, Wait Till Next Year (New York: Random House, 1960) (Box 14)
        - Correspondence, 1959-1964
        - Drafts, undated
          - Chapters, (4 folders)
          - Miscellaneous pages
        - Notes and research material, 1958, undated, (2 folders)
        - Outlines, undated, (2 folders)
        - Royalty statements, 1966 (Box 15)
        - Transcripts of audiotape interviews, undated
    - Musical biographies
      - The First, 1980-1982, undated
      - Play to Win, 1985
    - Poetry, 1961-1963, 1973-1974, undated
    - Speeches, 1957-1968, undated
  - Unidentified fragments and notes, undated
- Miscellany, 1942-1998 (Box 15-17)
  Correspondence, family papers, telegrams, military records, appointment books, awards and tributes, biographical material, cards and invitations, printed matter, newspaper clippings, and miscellaneous items.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Appointment books, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Awards and tributes, 1948-1964, 1971-1976, undated
  - Biographical material, 1961, undated
  - Cards and invitations, 1957-1971, undated
  - Carter, Lillian, 1978
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1948, 1956, 1962-1968, undated
    - Wallerstein, Caroline and David, 1951-1961, 1993
  - Death and funeral
    - Acknowledgment of condolences and tributes, 1972
    - Condolences, 1972
      - Cards
      - Letters, (2 folders) (Box 16)
      - Telegrams, (3 folders)
      - Telephone calls
    - Death certificate, 1972
    - In memoriam resolutions, 1972
    - Media tributes and newspaper clippings, 1972, 1983
    - Memorial service, 1972, 1984
    - Miscellany, 1973, undated
    - Tributes, 1972
  - Family papers
    - Robinson, Jackie (1946-1971), 1968-1971, 1995, undated
    - Robinson, Rachel
      - Correspondence, 1976, 1982-1987
      - Jackie Robinson: An Intimate Portrait, 1996
      - Miscellany, undated
  - Income taxes, 1947-1948
  - Marriage invitation, 1946
  - Military records
    - Court martial, 1944, 1958
    - Medical and personnel records
      - 1942-1943
      - 1944-1945, 1958, 1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - Personal history statement, 1943
  - Pasadena City College, Pasadena, Calif., 1998
  - Phonograph record, "Ode to Jackie," by Norman Fishelman, undated
  - University of California, Los Angeles, Calif., 1963, 1988
- 2023 Addition, 1954-2012 (Box 17)
  The 2023 Addition consists of a May 1958 letter from Robinson to President Dwight D. Eisenhower responding to the president's urge for "patience" on the topic of civil rights, and correspondence and memoranda regarding African American athlete Joe Yancey's nomination for the "Good Neighbor" Award given by Rhiengold Brewery (S. Liebmann Brewery).
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or material type.
  - Letter, Jackie Robinson to Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1958 (Box 17)
  - Rheingold "Good Neighbor" Award correspondence concerning Joe Yancey, 1954-1961, 2012 (Box 17)